hello everyone my name is Greg and I Dev
stuff welcome to episode 28 of the
tactics game in unity
we have a bug skip turn and on the
opening turn you can select your
character and move her around this is
happening because when we open the
command menu we are not taking into
account current round order because of
that we can take action in the enemy
turn
I think best course of action in this
case is to disable control on the enemy
turn all together because you will not
be able to control anything within the
enemy turn
in the round manager we want to disable
player controls
so when the player conclude his turn and
call next turn to give the turn to the
enemy we need to disable the mouse input
and when the enemy calculate his turn
and gives a turn to the player we need
to enable the player Mouse input
if we simply disable Mouse input it
should disable all the Play Input with
exception of right Mouse button bringing
menu
it's okay because aren't you will have
an AI we need this menu to be able to
skip the turn of the enemy
this is it on the enemy turn we cannot
do anything not gonna lie I'm a little
happy how it turned out well done
localized modular systems like this will
allow us this is just a few lines of
code and or change functionality
we have a victory condition for the
player and now we want to introduce a
transition between world map where
player will be managing his Squad and
like modifying his parameter stats etc
etc and the next mission the player
wants to participate
create a new scene called world map
using basic urp preset
on this world map we will be selecting
missions to complete create button
I will move it to be top left of the
screen but it doesn't matter really
right now
when I press this button we want to load
the mission 1 map and play it
create world map manager object
create an admission select component
inside this component we will be loading
the combat scenes
so remember essential combat scene is
the main scene in the functionality of
the combat and it must be loaded as a
main scene all the time when your player
must participate in the combat when you
type the name of the scene make sure it
is exactly the same name
and again this scene must be always
loaded for player combat to function
remember that for scene loading and
scene management to function you must
import the scene management Library
and type the name of the scene make sure
it is exactly the same name
then you load a battle stage on which we
will have our battle
but the name of the battle stage will be
passed as a parameter because while
essential scene is always present for
our Combat 2 function the battle stage
will be changing so we will be passing
the name of the button stage as a
parameter and loading the battle stage
adhesively to the essential scene making
them coexist at the same time
in the editor set the button to switch
to the combat stage 1.
for our systems to function we must set
the scenes into the build setting
now let's test this
if we launch mission 1 it will load the
combat essential and combat stage 1.
and we can easily change the first combo
stage and our changes will be applied
when we launch the stage
good so imagine you have multiple combat
stages and each of them have its own
environment or objectives for
demonstration let's make a new stage for
your game this duplicates the combat
stage 1 and make combat stage 2. inside
let's make a few changes to the
environment
and then add this mission to the build
at the bottom for this second stage
and let's test this
and as you can see different stage has
been loaded
so you can easily add new missions into
your game
this happens to the spirit will be
generous support of people on patreon
and members on YouTube if you want to
join them link to my patreon in the
description and join button available
right now on YouTube good we can select
and load the mission from the world map
how about we make our play be able to
win the combat and go back to the world
map I want you to notice how easy it is
to debug or work with the combat stage
simply launch combat essential scene and
add stage you want to debug additively
and this is it
now inside the victory condition manager
when we are victorious we want to open
some panel which will allow us to go
back to the world map
let's make method called Victory
and make a field for the panel
inside Victory method shows the panel
make the panel on the scene
add some text to congratulate player
and add button which if we press we will
go back to the world map
let's put return to world map process
for now into the victory condition
manager
and in the new method call scene manager
and load world map
Let's test this
it works now let's test if it will work
if I launch the game and try to win the
combat stage by defeating the enemies
I forgot to add the victory panel
reference
everything works but we have a small
issue we need to disable the control
because when I'm Victorious I still can
select my character and control them
around
not a problem simply reference the mouse
control in the vector condition script
and disable them
there is still an issue that it kept the
last character selected but don't worry
in the next episode we will be expanding
in the on the control scheme
good this is it for this episode if you
have any questions or any ideas about
code please leave a comment below if you
want to support me further link to the
patreon in the description special thank
you to the Salt hash do and Stormbreaker
9000 for their generous support his best
regards see in the next episode